あっ もしかして！
Could it be?
サクラちゃん 誤解だってばよ…。
Sakura-chan, you've got it all wrong.
のぞきなんて してねえってばよ！
I'm not peeking!
((ナルト～ッ！
Naruto!
ああ…。
And here I told you not to...
not to... not to...
(だから あれほど言ったのに…))
Oww!
痛い痛い！
許して サクラちゃん…。
Forgive me... Sakura-chan.
Sakura-chan...!
サクラちゃん… たぁ～っ！
Is it morning already...?
もう 朝か。
なんか 寝た気がしねえってばよ。
I don't... feel like I slept at all...
アイツ もう起きたのか…。
Did he get up already...?
ん？
《ねえ！
His stuff...
サイの荷物がねえ！
Sai's stuff is gone...
アイツ どこに行ったんだ!?》
Where... did he go?!
Morning, Naruto-kun.
おはよう ナルト君。
ヤマト隊長！
C-Captain Yamato...
That jerk, that jerk Sai...
あの野郎が…
あぁ サイの野郎が…！
Sai's outside.
サイなら外だ。
あ？
Your timing's perfect. I've got something
I want to ask you to do for me...
ちょうどよかった。
キミに頼みたいことがあるんだが…。
You are my friend.
you are my friend
Ah that day's dream...
aa ano hi no yume
You haven't forgotten it, have you?
ima demo mada wasuretenain deshou
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah it had just started your one longest way.
aa hajimatta bakka kimi no one longest way
Woah, I'm starting on a journey now!
woah ima tabidatsu yo
EVERDAY hereafter is a shining day.
everyday kono saki mo shining day
Unchanging singin', a bright morning smile.
kawarazu singin' hikaru asa no smile
This is the last farewell on funny days.
kore de miosame no funny days
Leaping into the future I see. Go far, dream of my heart.
tobidatsu future mezashita go far kokoro no dream of
I'll go the distance, the endless sky is blue.
i'll go the distance mihatenu sora wa blue
I've hitched a ride on the star ship, this is the best forever trip.
norikonda star ship kore ga saigo no forever trip
You are my friend.
you are my friend
Ah that day's dream...
aa ano hi no yume
You haven't forotten it, have you?
ima demo mada wasuretenai deshou
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah, it had just started your one longest way.
aa hajimatta bakka kimi no one longest way
Woah, I'm starting on a journey now!
woah ima tabidatsu yo
Thank you my friend.
thank you my friend
Ah even now,
aa ano hi no koto
I still remember that day.
ima demo mada oboeteru kara
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah those days that will never come back.
aa mou nidoto sou modoranai days
Woah I'll go the distance!
woah i'll go the distance
Untitled
(サクラ)へぇ～。
Wow...
絵なんか描くんだ。
So you draw.
何か用ですか？
Is there something you want?
口は悪いくせに
繊細なところもあるのね。
You're foul-mouthed,
but you've also got a sensitive side, huh?
フフッ 意外。
That's a surprise.
その作り笑い➡
That fake smile...
So you're still not through hitting me, huh?
まだ 殴り足りなかったんですか？
ボクのこと。
ちょっとね。
Not quite...
(サクラ)冗談！
ちょっと絵を見にきただけ。
I'm kidding!
I just came to check out your picture.
I was wondering what you were drawing.
(サクラ)どんなもんかと思ってね。
(サイ)そう…。
I see...
こんなところで描いてるから
風景画だと思ってたら➡
At first, I thought you were drawing a landscape
since you're drawing out here...
これ抽象画ね。
But it's an abstract, huh?
(サクラ)この絵
タイトルは なんていうの？
What's the title of this drawing?
You haven't decided on one yet?
まだ 決めてない？
さぁ？
I don't know.
You don't know...?
さぁ？ って
この絵のタイトルよ 題名！
The name of this drawing, a title.
You've got something in mind, don't you?
(サクラ)なんか 考えてるんでしょ。
笑ったりしないから教えて。
I won't laugh, so tell me.
I've got nothing like that.
そんなものないよ。
(サクラ)え？
What?!
I've drawn tens of thousands
of pictures...
(サイ)今まで 何千何万と
描いてきたけど➡
タイトルなんて つけたことないよ。
but I've never given one a title.
(サイ)だから この絵にも…。
So this doesn't have one, either...
Really?
ふ～ん…。
But you're supposed to give
a title to a picture, right?
(サクラ)でも 絵には
普通 題名をつけるものでしょ？
If it's a portrait,
you give it the name of the person...
肖像画だと
その人の名前とか➡
Or with other pictures,
それ以外の絵でも
そのときの状況や➡
you use the situation,
your feelings or emotions at the time...
自分の気持とか 感情とか…。
To be exact, I couldn't title
one of my drawings even if I wanted to...
正確には タイトルをつけようとしても
つけられないんだ。
Nothing comes to mind.
I don't... feel anything.
(サイ)何も思い浮かばない
何も感じないんだよ。
(サイ)何も…。
Nothing...
No wonder you can only say
such callous things!
どおりで だから無神経なこと
ばっかり言えるんだな。
It's about time for us to leave!
そろそろ出発だってばよ！
Captain Yamato told me
to come get you.
ヤマト隊長が呼んでこいってさ。
Right.
(サクラ)うん。
ふんっ！ こんな絵
たいしたことねえってばよ！
This drawing's nothing special!
そうですね。
You're right...
Just like your dick.
キミのチンチンと同じですよ。
カッ！ うぅ… 正直に
はっきり言う…➡
I'm going to be straight with you!
I can't stand you!
オレは テメエが嫌いだ！
If you've got a problem,
文句あんなら
作り笑いなんかしてねえで➡
stop the fake smiles
and tell me straight to my face!
正直に はっきり言いやがれ！
I'll take you on anytime
you want to fight!
ケンカなら いつでも買ってやる！
Oh... You want to fight?!
おっ！ やるってのか？
I've got...
(サイ)文句…。
no problem with you.
そんなものないよ。
え？
I don't care about you at all.
(サイ)キミのことなんて
ホントに なんとも思ってない。
Please go on ahead.
先に行っててください。
ボクも片したら すぐに行きます。
I'll catch up once I've tidied up.
I'll help.
手伝うわ。
This... isn't printed.
(サクラ)これ 印刷じゃないわね。
これも あなたが描いたの？
Did you draw this, too?
Yes.
(サイ)あぁ。
へぇ～ 絵本か。
Wow, it's a picture book, huh?
That looks cool.
(サクラ)おもしろそう！
ふんっ！
Oh! Say...
(サクラ)あ あのさ それ 行く途中に
見せてもらってもいい？
can I take a look
at it along the way?
I can't let you see it.
それは ダメだよ。
これ まだ完成してないから。
It's not finished yet...
And I don't hand this over to people.
それに 人には
渡さないことにしてるんだ。
This is my Brother's book, so...
(サイ)これは 兄さんのだからね。
《自分で描いたって
言ってたのに…》
But he said he drew it himself...
What's he talking about?
《コイツ なに言ってんだ？》
"Best Hot Water"
Thank you... Please come again...
(女将)おおきに またおいでやす。
So, has your unity improved?
みんな 親睦は深まったかな？
アハ アハハ！
なんで こんなヤツと！
Why do we have to be with this guy?
やっぱり 恐怖による支配のほうが
よかったかな？
So would you have preferred
control by fear?
I-It's okay. Our unity has improved!
大丈夫！ ちゃんと
親睦 深まったってばよ！ ハハハ…。
楽しそうですね ナルト君。
何 言ってんの！
Naruto-kun looks like he's enjoying himself...
What're you talking about?
That's a fake smile
any way you look at it.
(サクラ)どう見ても
作り笑いじゃない！
Really?
(サイ)そうなんですか？
You yourself said that
a smile is the best way
厄介ごとをやりすごすには
笑顔がいちばん！
to get through a tough situation, right?
あなた 自分で言ってたでしょ？
Oh yeah.
そうでしたね。
ハハハハハ…。
うん。
((何も感じないんだよ。
I don't feel anything.
I don't care about you at all.
(キミのことなんて
ホントに なんとも思ってない))
(ヤマト)そろそろかな。
It's just about time.
どうしたんです？ ヤマト隊長。
What is it, Captain Yamato?
This way.
(ヤマト)こっちだ。
えっ？
Huh?
Hurry up!
(ヤマト)早く。
あぁ わかったってばよ。
O-Okay!
Why are we going to the trouble
of coming through here...?
なんで
わざわざ こんなところを…。
ギャーッ!!
Captain Yamato!
What's the meaning of this?!
(サクラ)ヤマト隊長！
どういうことですか？
I think the path we were on
was the right way.
もとの道で
合ってると思いますけど。 隊長！
Captain!
I'm sure Tsunade-sama has told you.
綱手様が言ったはずだよ。
それって 何の話だ？
What're you talking about?
(ヤマト)サクラが得た情報は
ワナかもしれないって話だ。
The information Sakura
got might be a trap.
There's a possibility that
the Akatsuki might be...
(ヤマト)いざ 天地橋に着いてみたら
暁が待ち伏せしてる…。
waiting to ambush us
at the Tenchi Bridge.
その可能性もあるということだ。
They might be after you, Naruto-kun.
ナルト君 キミを狙ってね。
No way...
まさか…。
可能性は低いと思うけど
用心に こしたことはないからね。
I don't think there's a great possibility,
but you can never be too careful.
We'll proceed along a covert route
as much as possible
(ヤマト)ここから 天地橋までは➡
できるだけ
人目につかないルートを進むからね。
until we reach the Tenchi Bridge.
Right, got it.
あぁ！ わかったってばよ。
I guess this spot is okay.
このあたりで いいかな？
Huh?
えっ？
まさか…。
Don't tell me...
今夜は ここで休むよ。
えぇ～っ!?
We'll rest here tonight.
What?!
If we're going to camp out,
いや 野宿すんなら
こんなだだっ広い所じゃなくて➡
we should use the cave we just passed by
instead of this wide open area...
さっき 通り過ぎた所に
洞窟があって…。
Step back, everyone.
みんな 少し離れてて。
木遁 四柱家の術！
Wood Style: Four Pillar House Jutsu!
We'll camp out here tonight.
(ヤマト)今日は ここで野宿だね。
こういうのって
野宿って いわないんじゃない？
I don't think you can call something
like this camping out.
おぉ～。
すご～い！
This is amazing...
Wow, so this is what it looks
like on the inside.
へぇ～ 中は こうなってんのか。
(サクラ)結構 広いのね。
It's quite spacious, isn't it?
I think our room just might
hold some promise.
こりゃあ 部屋のほうも
期待できるってばよ。
ん？ あそこだ！
Welcome
Team Kakashi
Over there...
あれ？
(サクラ)意外に 中は殺風景ね。
Huh?
It's surprisingly bare, isn't it?
W-Well, it's better than sleeping outside.
まぁ 野宿よりは マシだってばよ。
そうね。
You're right.
ふぁ～ ひと休み ひと休み。
Break time, break time!
これで 風呂でもあれば…。
Now if only we had a bath, too.
Is there something you want?
何か用ですか？
フン！
Nothing at all!
何でもねえ。
はぁ…。
(ヤマト)みんな 少し集まってくれ。
Gather around, everyone.
And I want to ask
you something, Sakura.
それと サクラ
キミに聞いておきたいことがある。
What is it?
なんですか？
It's about the Akatsuki's Sasori.
暁のサソリについてだよ。
Sasori...
サソリ…。
I wanted to ask you sooner,
(ヤマト)
早く聞いておきたかったけど➡
but I promised that we weren't going to
talk about stuff like that yesterday.
昨日は そういう話はしないって
約束だったからね。
今日は
ゆっくり話してもらうよ。
I want you to tell me everything today...
目の前でサソリを見たのは
キミだけだったからね。
You're the only one who's ever
seen Sasori in person, after all...
はい。
Yes, sir.
(ヤマト)砂隠れから サソリのファイルは
一応受け取ったけど➡
For the time being,
I've received a file on
Sasori from the Hidden Sand...
ヤツの性格や言動
仕草や癖なんかがあったら➡
But tell me in as much detail
as you can
about his personality, behavior,
mannerisms and habits if he has any.
なるべく詳しく教えてくれ。
どういうことだってばよ。
What's this about?
大蛇丸の中に入り込んでるスパイは➡
The spy who's infiltrated
Orochimaru's organization thinks
Sasori is going to meet him
at the Tenchi Bridge.
天地橋に サソリが来ると
思っている。
They might see us through immediately,
(ヤマト)すぐに
見抜かれるかもしれないが➡
サソリに変化して
近づいたほうがいいからね。
but it's probably best to approach
by transforming into Sasori.
If Sasori doesn't show up
at the Tenchi Bridge,
もし サソリが
天地橋に現れなければ➡
then the spy might not, either...
相手も現れないかもしれない。
There's a distinct possibility.
その可能性は十分にある。
それじゃあ 意味ねえってばよ。
Then there'd be no point.
スパイは 相当のリスクを伴なう
行為だからね。
Being a spy is a very risky act, after all.
相手も かなり慎重になってる
ってことさ。
Which means the spy is probably
being quite cautious.
それじゃあ サソリには
ヤマト隊長が変化すんのか。
Then are you going to transform
into Sasori, Captain Yamato?
I'll probably have to.
そうなるだろうね。
サソリは 常に このヒルコという傀儡を
まとっていたそうだからね。
It seems he always remained
hidden inside this Hiruko puppet.
木遁忍術を使えるボクが
適任だろう。
So I'm probably the right one for this
since I can use the Wood Style Ninjutsu.
(サクラ)そうですね。
You're right.
And also, assuming this turns out
to be an Akatsuki trap...
それに 万が一
暁の罠という場合も想定して➡
I'll approach him alone at first.
ボクが まず １人で近づく。
((サソリ : 草隠れの里にある
天地橋に➡
At midday in ten days,
go to the Tenchi Bridge
located in the Village Hidden
in the Grass!
10日後の真昼に行け。
どういうこと？
What do you mean?
大蛇丸の部下に
オレのスパイがいる。
I've got a spy working as one
of Orochimaru's subordinates...
I was supposed to rendezvous...
with him... there...
(そこで ソイツと
落ち合う… ことに… なってる))
The way he talked being near death...
死に際の あの言い方。
I don't think he was lying...
たぶん ウソじゃないと思うけど…。
(サクラ)砂の里にも 由良っていう
暁のスパイがいたのは確かだし。
And there was indeed a spy
called Yuura in the Sand Village...
This is just assuming
something goes wrong.
(ヤマト)あくまでも
万が一を想定してのことだ。
You guys stand by until
I give you instructions.
キミたちは ボクの指示があるまで
待機しててくれ。
Either way, there's no doubting...
(サイ)どちらにしても そのスパイ…。
相当のやり手に
間違いないでしょうね。
that spy is probably
considerably powerful.
…やってやるってばよ！
Let's do this!
Now then...
さて ここからが本題だ。
Now for the main issue...
今回の任務を
もう少し 具体的に言うとだね➡
Let me explain the mission in
a little more detail.
目標は あくまでも
逮捕であって➡
Our goal is just to arrest the target.
We must not let him die,
even if we end up having to fight.
ターゲットを 死傷させてはならない。
もし 戦闘になったとしてもだ。
We'll lose an important source of
information if the target is killed.
殺してしまえば
大切な情報源が➡
失われることになるからね。
そして この手の任務は➡
And a mission like this is more difficult
than just killing an enemy.
敵を倒すより 困難だ。
As this is a delicate mission,
I will make the first move.
デリケートな任務だけに
まずは ボクが突入役だ。
そして キミたちは支援役。
And you guys will be my back-up...
作戦は 簡単。
第一 ボクが ターゲットを拘束する。
The strategy is simple.
First, I restrain the target.
第二 もし ボクが
ターゲットの拘束をし損ね➡
Second, if I should fail
to restrain the target
and this turns into a battle,
戦闘になった場合。
キミたちも 戦闘行動に移行しろ。
you guys shift to battle formation.
I will give you a signal when
I want you to do this.
そのタイミングは ボクが合図する。
そして 第二の場合においては➡
And in the event of the second case,
you are to operate with
the Buddy System.
常に バディシステムで行動する。
ん？ バ… バディ シ システム？
"B-Buddy System"?
(ヤマト)１人が動くときは
相棒が 必ず援護する。
When one person takes action,
a partner always backs you up.
Reciprocal back-up is
a fundamental rule.
相互支援が 原則だ。
知ってるだろう？
You know about this, don't you?
Oh, yeah! That, huh?
ん… あぁ
あれね あれ！
あ… アハハ…。
しっかりしてよね。
Get it together, will you?
Now I'm going to determine
the Buddy Teams.
(ヤマト)で そのバディチームを
今決めておく。
まずは ボクと サクラのチーム。
First, Sakura and I will be one team!
それに ナルトと サイのチームだ。
And...
the other team will be...
Naruto and Sai!
《オレが… コイツと？》
Me...?
with him...?
Reach for it, reach for it, far away.
todoke todoke tooku e
Now I trust these revived tears to you.
ima wo kishikaisei namida azukete
It begins.
hajimare
A long, long story about you
nagai nagai kimi monogatari
"Tears", "tears".
namidatte namidatte
I want to shed them in happy times
ureshii toki ni nagashitai
So what if I want them to float in pretty puddles?
kirei na mizutamari ukabetai no wa nani
The southern sky,
minami no sora ni
It twinkles.
matataiteiru
From all of the stars meeting.
hoshi no kazu hodo no deai kara
Learning about love, receiving a map.
ai wo manandari chizu wo morattari
Are connected.
tsunagatteku
Reach for it, reach for it, far away.
todoke todoke tooku e
Now I trust these revived tears to you.
ima wo kishikaisei namida azukete
Someday a new page will turn.
itsuka mekuru peeji ni
I'm sure it'll be filled with lots of people
kitto takusan no hito ga afureru
It begins,
hajimare
A long, long story about you.
nagai nagai kimi monogatari
Next Episode
You bastard! Don't you know
what the word comrade is?
やぁ みんな 今日はボクが➡
Of course! I could explain it
to you if you like.
忍五大国について
説明するよ。
That's not what I mean!
忍五大国とは➡
Please don't blame your lack
of individual competence on others.
強大な隠れ里を有する
五つの国➡
What?!
つまり
我らが火の国 木ノ葉隠れの里。
It isn't ideal to fight while
protecting someone
who has lost his cool.
同盟国の風の国 砂隠れの里。
All I did was consider the best way
to successfully complete the mission,
それに 土の国 岩隠れの里。
make a judgment and take action.
I'll never acknowledge you!
雷の国 雲隠れの里。
I wonder what Sasuke-kun would've done.
水の国 霧隠れの里の➡
Simulation
Next episode: "Simulation"
五つをさす言葉だ。
この五大国の里の長だけに
許された➡
NINJA ACADEMY
SPECIAL CLASS
最強の忍の称号が 影。
"THE FIVE GREAT NATIONS"
Hi, everyone. Today I'm going to talk
about the Five Great Nations.
五人の影を合わせて➡
五影とよぶんだ。
それじゃあ 問題を出すよ。
The Five Great Nations are the five nations
containing the powerful Hidden Villages.
Namely,
there's the Land of Fire
with our Village Hidden in Leaves.
There's the Land of Wind
with the Village Hidden in Sand.
(ヤマト)正解は ご覧のとおり。
There's also the Land of Earth
with the Village Hidden in Stones.
みんな できたかな？
できなかった人は…➡
There's the Land of Lightning
with the Village Hidden in Clouds.
ちゃんと復習するようにね。
And there's the Land of Water
with the Village Hidden in Mist.
These make up
the Five Great Nations.
The title of the most powerful shinobi
known as the “Kage” is granted
only to the leaders of these villages
in the Five Great Nations.
Al five of these Kages
collectively known as the “Five Kages”.
Kazekage, Tsuchikage, Hokage, Raikage, Mizukage
Now let me give you a question.
"Do you know which headband
goes with what village?"
Here's the answer.
STONE         CLOUD
LEAF
SAND         MIST
Did you guys get it?
Those who didn't...
had better review it thoroughly.